Register of the Museum of Russian Culture Miscellaneous Materials Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Museum of Russian Culture miscellaneous materials collection,
1867-1977
2001C79
4 microfilm reels (0.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Papers of various Russians and Russian émigrés, including correspondence, writings, personal documents, and photographs, relating to Russian history and culture, Russian participation in World War I, the Russian Revolution and Civil War, and Russian émigré affairs. Collected by the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is a compilation of papers of individual persons or organizations that were too small in volume to be accessioned separately. The Petr Mikhailov papers contain the oldest materials, dating from the second half of the 19th century, although the Agapii Goncharenko collection, consisting primarily of later clippings, also refers to this period, Goncharenko being a pioneer of the Russian-language press in America. Most of the papers are of a biographical or genealogical nature, although there is also a folder of documents relating to the Society of Russian Engineers and Technicians on the Island of Cyprus (Obshchestvo russkikh inzhenerov i tekhnikov na o. Kipr).
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russia--History.; Russia--Civilization.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russians in foreign countries.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; World War, 1914-1918.
Other Index Terms Related to this Collection
Museum of Russian Culture (San Francisco, Calif.).
Series Description
- Mitrofan M. Afanasiev File, 1937-1952. (Box 1)
  M. M. Afanasiev was born in Russia on 21 November 1900. In 1920 he left Russia and in 1927 he was awarded the Degree of Agricultural Engineer from the Higher School of Agriculture (Brno, Czechoslovakia). In 1930 he arrived in the United States and in June 1937 he received his Ph.D. (plant pathology, botany and organic chemistry) from the University of Nebraska. From 1936 he worked as a Plant Pathologist and Professor of Plant Pathology at the Montana State College. Curriculum vitae and writings, divided into articles and leaflets
- Vladimir Ivanovich Azarov File, 1941-1942. (Box 2)
  V. I. Azarov, also known as William Azaroff (Pen name: Nevozvrashchenets?), was an agronomist and a member of the VTsIK of the Communist Party of the USSR. He personally knew V. I. Lenin and I. V. Stalin. From 1928 to 1930(?) he worked as a Soviet Trade representative in Riga. In 1930(?) he defected to the West, and later emigrated to the United States. Correspondence, writings, and one print
- Aleksandr D. Bilimovich File, 1953-1960 and undated. (Box 3)
  Professor A. D. Bilimovich was a Russian émigré economist and writer, author of the book Marksizm: Izlozhenie i kritika. Writings, arranged chronologically by title
- Vasilii Vladimirovich Bolgarskii File, 1913-1953. (Box 4)
  V. V. Bolgarskii was a lecturer in chemistry and physics in various educational institutions in Harbin, China. He established a number of physics and chemistry laboratories and published numerous textbooks on chemistry and physics. Birth certificate, curriculum vitae, diploma, employment records, invitation, and letters of recommendation, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Aleksandr Aleksandrovich Bubnov File, 1915-1951. (Box 5)
  The documents of Colonel A. A. Bubnov relate primarily to the history of the 9-aia Sibirskaia Strelkovaia Artilleriiskaia brigada in the First World War. Certificates, correspondence, description of battles, financial records, liquidation documents, list of officers, orders, service records
- Agapii Goncharenko File, 1913-1950. (Box 6)
  Father Agapii Goncharenko (Andrei Onufrievich Goncharenko, aka Agapius Honcharenko) was the publisher of the first Russian language newspaper in the United States - the Alaska Herald (later Svoboda). Clipping and biographical articles about him
- Taras Petrovich Gordeev (Gordeeff) File, 1910?-1970. (Box 7)
  T. P. Gordeev was a soil scientist in Manchuria and teacher of natural sciences in different educational institutions in Harbin, China. Biographical file, correspondence, subject file, photographs, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Ivan Aleksandrovich Il'in File, 1951-1952. (Box 8)
  Russian émigré philosopher, writer and publicist. Correspondence and writings
- Aleksandr Dmitrievich Kozhukhar' File, 1902-1973. (Box 9)
  The papers of A. D. Kozhukhar', also know as Alexander Kojuhare, reflect the activities of the Russian Orthodox Church in China, and include photographs of Harbin, China, and Russian clergymen. Certificates and diplomas, and photographs
- Pavel Viacheslavovich Lashkov File, 1908-1923. (Box 10)
  P. V. Lashkov (Paul Lashkoff) served in the Siberian Flotilla in 1919-1923. Certificates and service records, and photographs
- Ivan Vasil'evich Maiorov File, 1936 and undated. (Box 11)
  I. V. Maiorov was a prominent figure in the cooperation movement in Siberia. Biographical note and writings
- Adelaida Tikhonovna Martynova File, 1926-1940. (Box 12)
  A. T. Martynova (Martinoff) was a member of several Russian charitable organizations, in particular the Committee for the Benefit of the Russian Disabled Veterans of the World War. Clippings, correspondence, family file, and membership cards, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Petr Akekseevich Mikhailov File, 1867-1929. (Box 13)
  P. A. Mikhailov was born on 12 January 1889, and served in various ranks in different military units. Biographical file, military decorations, and photographs, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Obshchestvo Russkikh inzhenerov i tekhnikov na o. Kipr File, 1920-1953. (Box 14)
  This collection contains official records of the Obshchestvo Russkikh inzhenerov i tekhnikov na o. Kipr donated by its former secretary, Arkadii Anatol'evich Lenchevskii. Certificate, charter, financial statements, and minutes of meetings
- Pavel Fedorovich Orlov File, 1929-1964. (Box 15)
  Doctor P. F. Orlov, also known as Paul F. Orlov, had medical practices in Harbin and Shanghai, China, specializing in nervous, mental and internal diseases. He later emigrated to the United States. Biographical file, correspondence, printed matter, and speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Podushkin Family File, 1867-1914. (Box 16)
  This collection contains records of the three generations of the Podushkin family of Russian naval officers. Certificates, power of attorney, service and tax records, arranged alphabetically by name of family member
- Sentianin Family File, 1901-1977. (Box 17)
  Includes papers of Vasilii Evgrafovich Sentianin, head of the Pension Department of the Chinese Eastern Railway administration (KVZhD), and Evgeniia Aleksandrovna Sentianina (pen name E. Aleksandrova), well-known Russian journalist who worked in China in 1927-1945 and was the mother of writer Valerii Pereleshin (Salatko-Petrishche). She emigrated to Brazil, where she died in 1980. Correspondence, notebook, scrapbook, writings, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by name of family member in a family file; and photographs
- Marina Valery File, 1927-1948. (Box 18)
  Marina Valery (Valeri), née Marina Petrashova (Petraschow), was a child actress of various talents who performed in displaced persons camps in Allied occupation zones. Biographical file and photographs
Container List
- MITROFAN M. AFANASIEV FILE, 1937-1952 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, n.d. (Folder 1: 1)
  - Writings
    - Articles
      - "Comparative Physiology of Actinomyces in Relation to Potato Scab," abstract of dissertation, University of Nebraska, 1937. (Folder 1: 2)
        Printed copy
      - "Comparative Physiology of Actinomyces in Relation to Potato Scab," Nebraska Agriculture Experiment Station Research Bulletin 92, 1937 August. (Folder 1: 3)
      - "Method of Isolating Single Hyphal Tips of Actinomyces," Phytopathology, 1937 December. (Folder 1: 4)
      - "Influence of Rotations under Irrigation on Potato Scab, Rhizoctonia, and Fusarium Wilt," Nebraska Agriculture Experiment Station Research Bulletin 317, 1938 May. (Folder 1: 5)
      - "The Effect of Preceding Crops on the Amount of Seedling Diseases of Sugar Beets," Annals of the American Society of SugarBeet Technologists, 1942. (Folder 1: 6)
      - "The Relation of Phosphorus and Nitrogen Ratio to the Amount of Seedling Diseases of Sugar Beets," Annals of the American Society of SugarBeet Technologists, 1942. (Folder 1: 7)
      - "Control of Seedling Diseases of Sugar Beets in Montana," Phytopathology, 1942 June. (Folder 1: 8)
      - "Potato Diseases in Montana and Their Control," Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 166, 1942 June. (Folder 1: 9)
      - "The Effect of Alfalfa on Succeeding Sugar Beets at Huntley (Montana) Field Station," Through the Leaves, 1943 May-June. (Folder 1: 10)
      - "Handbook of Plant Diseases and Their Control for Montana," Montana Agricultural Extension Service Bulletin 216, 1943 June. (Folder 1: 11)
      - "Diseases of Sugar Beets in Crop Rotations at the Huntley Branch Station, Huntley, Montana from 1936 to 1941," Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 419 (Technical), 1943 November. (Folder 1: 12)
      - "Yellows, a Non-Infectious Disease of the Progressive Everbearing Strawberry in Montana," Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 424 (Technical), 1944 December. (Folder 1: 13)
      - "Montana Progressive Strawberry: A Yellows-Resistant, Everbearing Variety Developed During Research of Yellows," Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 181, 1945 March. (Folder 1: 14)
      - "Sugar Beets Diseases and their Control in Montana," Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 427, 1945 March. (Folder 1: 15)
      - "Effect of Different Soil and Seed Treatments on the Control of Seedling Diseases of Sugar Beets Under Controlled Conditions," Proceedings American Society of Sugar Beet Technologists, 1946. (Folder 1: 16)
      - "Growing Sugar Beets Following Alfalfa in Montana," Proceedings American Society of Sugar Beet Technologists, 1946. (Folder 1: 17)
      - "Time of Infection and Accumulative Effect of Rhizoctonia on Successive Crops of Potatoes," American Potato Journal, 1947 January. (Folder 1: 18)
      - "The Relation of Six Groups of Fungi to Seedling Diseases of Sugar Beets in Montana," Phytopathology, 1948 March. (Folder 1: 19)
      - "Resistance and Soil Treatments for Control of Rhizoctonia of Sugar Beets," Proceedings American Society of Sugar Beet Technologists, 1952. (Folder 1: 20)
      - "Bean Virus 2 (Yellow) on Great Northern Bean in Montana," Phytopathology, 1952 February. (Folder 1: 21)
    - Leaflets, n.d. (Folder 1: 22)
      Issued by the Montana Extension Service in Agriculture and Home Economics about fruit, vegetables, and cereals diseases. Printed copies
- VLADIMIR IVANOVICH AZAROV FILE, 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Petr Filaretovich Konstantinov, 1942. (Folder 2: 1)
    Includes attachments
  - Writings
    - General, n.d. (Folder 2: 2)
      Short stories. Holograph
    - "Moi vstrechi so Stalinym i ego zhenoi," n.d. (Folder 2: 3)
      Typescript
  - Photograph, 1941. (Folder 2: 4)
    One print of an unidentified person
- ALEKSANDR D. BILIMOVICH FILE, 1953-1960 and undated. (Box 3)
  Writings
  - "Bibliografiia: Professor S. N. Prokopovich. Narodnoe khoziaistvo SSSR," Russkaia Zhizn', 1953 May 13-15. (Folder 3: 1)
  - Marksizm (Izlozhenie i kritika), 1954 and undated
    - Holograph, n.d. (Folder 3: 2)
    - Printed copy, 1954 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Kooperatsiia v Rossii do, vo vremia i posle Bol'shevikov, 1955. (Folder 3: 4)
  - Ekonomicheskii stroi osvobozhdennoi Rossii, 1960. (Folder 3: 5)
- VASILII VLADIMIROVICH BOLGARSKII FILE, 1913-1953 (Box 4)
  - Birth certificate, 1913. (Folder 4: 1)
    Includes birth certificate of his mother, Feoktista Vasil'evna Bolgarskaia
  - Curriculum vitae, 1953 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Declaration to the Brazilian government, n.d. (Folder 4: 3)
  - Diploma issued by Kazan University, Russia, 1913 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Employment records, 1919-1946 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Invitation to the meeting of the Russian Medical Society of Harbin, 1941 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1935-1936 (Folder 4: 7)
- ALEKSANDR ALEKSANDROVICH BUBNOV FILE, 1915-1951. (Box-folder 5: 1)
  Military records include certificates, correspondence, financial documents, liquidation documents, list of officers, and orders of the 9-aia Sibirskaia Strelkovaia General-Fel'dtseikhmeistera Velikogo Kniazia Mikhaila Nikolaevicha Artilleriiskaia brigada. Also includes service records of Colonel Aleksandr Aleksandrovich Bubnov and description of the unit's first World War I battle on 6 February 1915. Original order of papers established by A. A. Bubnov retained
- AGAPII GONCHARENKO FILE, 1913-1950. (Box-folder 6: 1)
  Clipping and biographical articles about Agapii Goncharenko (Agapius Honcharenko)
- TARAS PETROVICH GORDEEV (GORDEEFF) FILE, 1910?-1970 (Box 7)
  - General (Folder 7: 1)
  - Biographical file, 1945-1970
    - Address in honor of his 85th birthday, 1960 (Folder 7: 2)
    - Biographical note (Folder 7: 3)
    - Identity papers. (Folder 7: 4)
      Includes translation of documents into Russian
  - Correspondence, 1923-1962
    - General
      - General (Folder 7: 5)
      - Greeting cards from Gordeev's students, 1931-1942 (Folder 7: 6)
    - Unidentified, 1923-1937 (Folder 7: 7)
    - Chinese Eastern Railway education department and teacher's union, 1925-1936 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Dumanskaia?, 1923 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Frolov, V. S., 1940 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Glukhov (Glouhoff), N. V., 1934-1956 (Folder 7: 11)
    - Golubtsova, M. O., 1955 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Gusev (Gooseff), A. A., 1930 (Folder 7: 13)
    - Koksharov, V. V., 1941-1942 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Levchenko, E.?, 1956 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Podobedova, A.?, 1962 (Folder 7: 16)
    - Ponosov, V. V., 1938-1962. (Folder 7: 17)
    - Shilova, S., 1936 (Folder 7: 18)
    - Terestchenko, Sinaida, 1957-1959 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Subject file
    - Bokova, L. N., 1969 (Folder 7: 20)
      Letters to T. N. Pokrovsky?
    - China--Social conditions--1644-1912. (Folder 7: 21)
      Diary of an unidentified person about plague in China in 1910-1911?. Includes attached photographs
    - Iona, Bishop of Hankow, October, 1967. (Folder 7: 22)
      Article about him in Pravoslavnyi Blagovestnik (San Francisco), #10
    - Skvortsov, B. V. (Folder 7: 23)
      Letters from V. L. Komarov and an unidentified person
    - Miscellany (Folder 7: 24)
  - Photographs
    - 19 prints depicting T. P. Gordeev (Folder 7: 25)
    - 43 prints depicting plague in China in 1910-1911?., See Subject file/China--Social conditions--1644-1912
- IVAN ALEKSANDROVICH IL'IN FILE, 1951-1952 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Writings, n.d.
    - "Edinyi front," n.d. (Folder 8: 2)
    - "Ivan Sergeevich Shmelev," n.d. (Folder 8: 3)
    - "Krizis sotsializma," Vozrozhdenie, n.d. (Folder 8: 4)
    - "Natsional-sotsializm," n.d. (Folder 8: 5)
    - "Pushkin v zhizni: 1799-1837," n.d. (Folder 8: 6)
    - "Radosti obshcheniia," Vozrozhdenie, n.d. (Folder 8: 7)
    - "Sistema rastleniia," Vozrozhdenie, n.d. (Folder 8: 8)
    - "Tverdost' razuma," n.d. (Folder 8: 9)
    - "Vera v Rossiiu," n.d. (Folder 8: 10)
- ALEKSANDR DMITRIEVICH KOZHUKHAR' FILE, 1902-1973 (Box 9)
  - Certificates and diplomas, 1902-1927. (Folder 9: 1)
    Includes some documents in Chinese
  - Photographs, 1909-1973
    - Album of prints probably depicting the Russian Orthodox Mission in Peking (Folder 9: 2)
    - 95 loose prints depicting A. D. Kozhukhar', Bishop Nestor, Archbishop Antonii, and other clergymen, Harbin, China, and unidentified persons and places (Folder 9: 3)
- PAVEL VIACHESLAVOVICH LASHKOV FILE, 1908-1923 (Box 10)
  - Certificates and service records, 1923 (Folder 10: 1)
  - Photographs, 1908-1915. (Folder 10: 2)
    One print depicting Karl-Fridrikh Karlovich Klesti and one print depicting Vadim Zhdanov (?)
- IVAN VASIL'EVICH MAIOROV FILE, 1936 and undated (Box 11)
  - Biographical note, n.d. (Folder 11: 1)
  - Writings, 1936 and undated
    - General (Folder 11: 2)
    - Memoirs, untitled, n.d. (Folder 11: 3)
      Holograph. Includes descriptions of village life in late 19th - early 20th century Russia, and stories entitled "Puteshestvie na Florishchevu Pustyn'," "Nasha shkola," "Obychai v derevne v 1881 godu"
    - Notebooks, 1936 and undated. (Folder 11: 4)
      Holograph. Includes citations from various authors about church history and his personal thoughts
- ADELAIDA TIKHONOVNA MARTYNOVA FILE, 1926-1940 (Box 12)
  - Clippings, 1934-1940. (Folder 12: 1)
    Articles about or mentioning A. T. Martynova
  - Correspondence, 1926-1940 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Family file - Martynov, Aleksandr Antonovich, husband (?), 1932-1936. (Folder 12: 3)
    Correspondence
  - Membership cards, 1927 (Folder 12: 4)
- PETR ALEKSEEVICH MIKHAILOV FILE, 1867-1929 (Box 13)
  - Biographical file, 1867-1919
    - Military records (Folder 13: 1)
    - Family file
      - Mikhailov, Aleksei Vasil'evich (father), 1867-1914 (Folder 13: 2)
      - Mikhailov, Arkadii Alekseevich (brother), 1918 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Miscellany. (Folder 13: 4)
      Includes a prayer of Russian officers and Russian bank-notes, 1898-1916
  - Military decorations, n.d. (Folder 13: 5)
  - Photographs, 1929 and undated. (Folder 13: 6)
    25 prints depicting the Shanghai Russian Regiment and unidentified persons and places
  - OBSHCHESTVO RUSSKIKH INZHENEROV I TEKHNIKOV NA O. KIPR FILE, 1920-1953. (Box-folder 14: 1)
    Minutes of meetings with attachments, including certificate of A. A. Lenchevskii, charter, and financial statements. Also includes a letter by A. A. Lenchevskii. Original order retained
- PAVEL FEDOROVICH ORLOV FILE, 1929-1964 (Box 15)
  - Biographical file, 1929-1940
    - Clippings, 1936-1940 (Folder 15: 1)
    - Employment records, 1929 and undated (Folder 15: 2)
    - Family file - Orlov (Orloff), N. F., brother
      - General (Folder 15: 3)
      - Speeches and writings
        - "I. P. Pavlov po lichnym vosspominaniiam," n.d. (Folder 15: 4)
          Draft of a speech written on the reverse side of letters to P. F. Orlov. Holograph
        - "Nasledstvennost' i ee znachenie," 1933. (Folder 15: 5)
    - Invitations for meetings of the Medical Society of Harbin and the Russian Medical Society of Shanghai (Folder 15: 6)
    - Savings account book, 1931 (Folder 15: 7)
    - Miscellany. (Folder 15: 8)
      Includes medical forms and letterheads from Orlov's medical practices
  - Correspondence, 1934-1936., See Biographical file/Family file/Speeches and writings/"I. P. Pavlov..."
  - Printed matter, 1929-1964
    - Brochures and flyers (Folder 15: 9)
    - Clippings about Russians in China, Japan, and the Philippines. (Folder 15: 10)
      Includes one issue of KitaiskoRusskaia Gazeta, 1947 May 1
    - Miscellany (Folder 15: 11)
  - Speeches and writings, 1936-1945
    - "Lechebnye faktory kurorta Tsindao," Dal'nevostochnyi vrachebnyi vestnik, #29-30, 1936. (Folder 15: 12)
    - "Ot kolybeli chelovechestva do nashikh dnei: Kratkii ocherk istorii meditsiny," Gun-Bao, 1936 October. (Folder 15: 13)
    - "Prekrasnaia priroda i klimat, komfort, uiut i spokoistvie," Shankhaiskaia zaria, 1940 September 6. (Folder 15: 14)
    - "Chto daiut Kursy Sester Miloserdiia," 1940 September 17. (Folder 15: 15)
    - "Neblagopoluchie na fronte zdraviia russkogo Shanhaia," 1945 September 8. (Folder 15: 16)
- PODUSHKIN FAMILY FILE, 1867-1914 (Box 16)
  - Genneman, Aleksandra Georgievna, 1885., Wife of G. S. Podushkin. (Folder 16: 1)
    Certificate
  - Podushkin, German Semenovich, 1890-1905. (Folder 16: 2)
    Marriage certificate and service records
  - Podushkin, Ivan Semenovich, 1914 (copy of the original dated 1827). (Folder 16: 3)
    Service records
  - Podushkin, Semen Ivanovich, 1867-1888. (Folder 16: 4)
    Power of attorney, service and tax records
- SENTIANIN FAMILY FILE, 1901-1977 (Box 17)
  - Family file
    - Sentianin, Vasilii Evgrafovich, 1901-1927. (Folder 17: 1)
      Scrapbook includes correspondence and clippings about him
    - Sentianina, Evgeniia Aleksandrovna
      - General (Folder 17: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1925-1977 (Folder 17: 3)
      - Notebook, n.d. (Folder 17: 4)
        Contains list of her personal acquaintances who were repatriated to the USSR
      - Writings
        - "Po iuzhnym moriam v Braziliiu," n.d. (Folder 17: 5)
          Incomplete typescript with introduction by Valerii Pereleshin
        - "S nasizhennyh mest," n.d. (Folder 17: 6)
          Typescript. Includes biographical note by Valerii Pereleshin
      - Miscellany. (Folder 17: 7)
        Includes translation of an article by Maria Pavlovan Korostovets and a water-color by her
  - Photographs, 1920-1930. (Folder 17: 8)
    One print depicting V. E. Sentianin and one print depicting Valerii Pereleshin, Iu. M. Volkov, his niece Liudmila and his sister Irina
- MARINA VALERY FILE, 1927-1948 (Box 18)
  - Biographical file, 1946-1948
    - Articles about Marina Valery, 1946-1947., See also identity papers (Folder 18: 1)
    - Clippings with concert announcements, 1946-1948 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Identity papers, 1946-1947. (Folder 18: 3)
      Includes articles about Marina Valery
    - Promotional materials
      - General (Folder 18: 4)
      - Posters (Folder 18: 5)
      - Programs (Folder 18: 6)
    - Repertory (Folder 18: 7)
  - Photographs, 1927-1948. (Folder 18: 8)
    36 prints depicting Marina Valery and her parents: Mariia Mitrofanovna Petrashova and Aleksandr Vasil'evich Petrashov